#### Contact

lasi, Romania +40728026899 (Mobile) cristian@nexusmedia.ro

www.linkedin.com/in/cristiansimionescu (LinkedIn) cristian.simionescu.me/ (Personal) github.com/Tensor-Reloaded (Personal) github.com/simi2525 (Personal)

## Top Skills

Deep Learning
PyTorch
C#

## Languages

Romanian (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional)

#### Certifications

Exam 70-483: Programming in C#

#### **Publications**

Prehospital Cerebrovascular Accident Detection using Artificial Intelligence Powered Mobile Devices

# Cristian Simionescu

Machine Learning PhD Student

Iaşi, Romania

## Summary

Artificial Intelligence Ph.D. student with +8 years of experience as a Software Engineer.

Always eager to work on projects that create value for as many people as possible, in both industry and academic settings.

Particularly interested in researching and applying Deep Learning methods. Staying up to date with the field's state-of-the-art.

# Experience

Faculty of Computer Science, Alexandru Ioan Cuza University of Iasi 5 years 1 month

University Assistant October 2023 - Present (1 month)

Iasi County, Romania

In my teaching role, I conduct classes on Probabilistic Programming and Modeling, Software Engineering, Machine Learning, Advanced Topics in Neural Networks, and Probability and Statistics.

## Teaching Collaborator

October 2018 - October 2023 (5 years 1 month)

Iasi County, Romania

Beginning with the academic year 2018-2019 I started teaching seminars and laboratories at the faculty. I taught several classes of Data Structures, Algorithm Design, Probabilistic Programming and Modeling and Software Engineering.

### **Programming Analyst**

January 2019 - August 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Iasi County, Romania

Alongside my research masters program I worked on a research internship position developing multiple Deep Learning state of the art techniques and projects.

Nexus Media srl 11 years 10 months

.NET Developer July 2015 - Present (8 years 4 months)

Iasi County, Romania

When I finished high-school I started working a full-time position inside the company. I started taking on complex projects, both existing and new ones, some of which consisted of me leading a development team.

## Assistant Programmer

January 2012 - July 2015 (3 years 7 months)

Iași, Romania

My first work experience in an office, working on simple maintenance tasks of various ERP products as well as creating product presentation websites in a part-time position.

Tensor Reloaded Group Coordinator July 2019 - Present (4 years 4 months) lasi, Romania

I created and began to expand a machine learning research group @FII. Coordinated and worked on multiple machine learning research projects.

Cluster IMAGO-MOL
Information Technology Consultant
February 2020 - February 2021 (1 year 1 month)
Iaşi, Romania

Consulting, proposing and implementing software for the REVERT project, code 848098, Horizon 2020 Program, Computer Science Researcher.

## Education

Universitatea "Alexandru Ioan Cuza" din Iași Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Computer Science · (2020 - 2023)

Universitatea "Alexandru Ioan Cuza" din Iași Master of Science - MS, Computer Science · (2018 - 2020)

Universitatea "Alexandru Ioan Cuza" din Iași Bachelor's degree, Computer Science (2015 - 2018) Richard Wurmbrand College, Iasi

High School Diploma, Mathematics and Computer Science · (2001 - 2015)